# Hiroko Yamaji Frontend Engineer

US phone #: +1 (424) 503-9710 Email: hiroko@hirokoymj.com Current Location: Tokyo, Japan

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/hirokoyamaji/

# **Summary:**

Experienced Frontend Engineer proficient in React.js, seeking a challenging role in California or Texas. With 15 years of experience in Los Angeles, I possess a deep understanding of US tech industry standards and best practices. I am a Google Cloud Certified Professional and a green card holder. Available to relocate within 6 weeks of a job offer.

#### **US Status:**

Green Card holder

# **Code Sample:**

https://www.hirokoymj.com https://github.com/hirokoymj/hiroko-web-frontend

#### **Technical Skills:**

Front-end: JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Apollo Client v3, Lodash, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Material UI v4

**Back-end**: Typescript, Node.js, Apollo Server v3, Mongoose **Database**: MongoDB Atlas, Cloud Databases on Google Cloud

**Cloud Platform**: Google Cloud Platform **Version Control**: Git, GitHub, GitLab

Software: Visual Studio Code, Slack, Google Meet, Microsoft Teams, JIRA, Confluence

# **Work Experience:**

Infosys Limited Japan Tokyo, Japan

May 2022 - Present

# Google Cloud Engineer (August 2022 - Present)

- Resolved 250+ GCP customer issues leveraging deep expertise in:
  - Serverless technologies (Cloud Run, App Engine)
  - Network optimization (Direct VPC Egress, Load Balancing, Private Google Access)
  - Data storage and management (Cloud SQL, Cloud Storage)
  - Identity and Access Management (IAM)
  - Client-side development (Node.js Client Library)

#### Frontend Engineer for React.js (May 2022 – August 2022)

- Built a React Query 4 based prototype for a new web application.
- Evaluated Redux state structure in client web applications and architected how to add new functions using *combineReducer* method.

Asurion Japan Tokyo, Japan

May 2021 – January 2022

Frontend Engineer (Contractor)

• Key technologies: React.js, Redux, TypeScript, Apollo client, GraphQL, Cypress

Software Engineer for React.js

- Key technologies: React.js, Redux, JavaScript, Apollo Client for GraphQL, Material-UI, Google Map API
- Worked in a small IT team with frontend engineers, a UI designer and DevOps members.
- Successfully refactored the Owner application with React v16 using React Hooks.
- Used Git commands daily to collaborate other developers. Rose a pull request to GitLab.

# Beachbody.com Santa Monica, CA

December 2017 - September 2018

Frontend Engineer

• Key technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, Gulp.js, Bootstrap 3, React.js

Strategic Partners Inc.

Northridge, CA

December 2016 - June 2017

Frontend Engineer

- Key technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Gulp.js, Bootstrap 3, React.js
- Successfully transformed a non-responsive into a fully responsive websites by 12 columns grid system.
- Built weather component by Open Weather API to display local weather forecast in a web application.

# Teleflora.com Los Angeles, CA

October 2009 - October 2016

Frontend Developer

- Key technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Sass, Gulp.js, Bootstrap3 and PHP.
- Created responsive landing pages with promo codes to facilitate Teleflora.com sales.

# MC Squared Los Angeles, CA

September 2006 – November 2007

Web Developer

• Key technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL.

Sony Electronics Inc. Santa Monica, CA

July 2005 – July 2006

Java Web Developer (Contractor)

# **Education:**

Santa Monica College Santa Monica, CA

February 2004 - June 2005

Certificate of Interactive Media

Yamawaki Gakuen Junior College Tokyo Japan

April 1989 – March 1991

Associate degree of Food Science

#### **Certifications:**

• Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Developer September 2024

• Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Architect January 2024

Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Database Engineer July 2023

Google Certified Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer
January 2023